brandz.com 2019-03-19

# brandZ | Privacy Policy

We’ve stopped what we are doing and creating your personalized BrandZ™ report, which will appear in your inbox soon.

BrandZ Privacy Policy

This website is operated by WPP. By using and visiting our website and by submitting your personal information to us you agree to us using your personal information as set out in this privacy policy.

[[If you just want to know about how we use cookies please click here](http://www.wpp.com/wpp/cookies.htm?&sa=D&ust=1544732256549000).]

We respect the privacy of users of our website and recognise that when you choose to provide us with information about yourself, you trust us to act in a responsible manner with that information. This privacy policy contains important information about how we use your personal information.

What information do we collect?

At times we may request that you voluntarily supply us with personal information. Generally this information is requested when you want us to provide you with information. When you register for an account we will request personal information about you.

We may gather the following information about you:

Name

Email address

Region preferences

Category preferences

IP address (a unique identifier for your computer or other device)

Mobile device ID

Information provided by you in relation to BrandZ publications

How do we use it?

We will use this information in the following ways:

to provide you with information that you have requested e.g. a newsletter, bulletins;

to respond to specific queries you may raise;

to provide you with better ways of accessing information from this website;

Send personalised push notifications to your mobile

[For how we use your information that is collected using cookies and similar technologies please see the "Cookies" [here](http://www.wpp.com/wpp/cookies.htm?&sa=D&ust=1544732256552000).]

Your Legal Rights

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. These include the right to:

\- Request access to your personal data.

\- Request correction of your personal data.

\- Request erasure of your personal data.

\- Object to processing of your personal data.

\- Request restriction of processing your personal data.

\- Request transfer of your personal data.

\- Right to withdraw consent.

You can see more about these rights at: [https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/?&sa=D&ust=1544732256554000) If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please email us at [brandz.website@wpp.com](mailto:brandz.website@wpp.com). 

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

Do we pass your information to third parties?

You consent to us sharing your personal data in the following circumstances:

(a) We may send your personal information to other group companies, affiliates and third parties to help us process your personal information for the purposes set out in this policy.

(b) We may disclose personal information to third parties when we reasonably believe we are required by law, and in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual unlawful or otherwise prohibited activities, including, but not limited to, fraud.

(c) If our business (or any part of it) is sold or transferred at any time, the personal data we hold may form part of the assets transferred although will still only be used in accordance with this policy. Further, in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, we may disclose your personal data to the prospective buyer or seller of such business or assets. We will ensure that the third parties who receive your personal information are required to keep it confidential.

Please be assured that, other than as set out here, we will not pass your personal data to a third party company without your prior consent.

How do we use your information for marketing?

We will be sending emails and push notifications of relevant content that may be of interest to you.

Where do we send your information?

We are a global company and therefore we may transfer your personal information to countries around the world including the US and other countries outside Europe. We will, where necessary, put in place appropriate safeguards to ensure your information is protected.

How long do we keep your information?

We will keep your information for a reasonable period for the purposes set out above.

Security

For your information we have certain security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and/or alteration of the information that we may collect. However, as effective as our security measures are, no security system is impenetrable. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data held by us; any sharing with us is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use good practice procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

Passwords

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you post comments, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Cookies

What are cookies?

We may use information obtained from cookies or similar technology. Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which we download onto your computer or device when you visit our website. Therefore, when we refer to "you" in this section we mean your computer. We can recognise these cookies on subsequent visits and they allow us to remember you.

Cookies come in many forms. We have set out below the main types and categories of cookies that are used. This section refers to all types and categories of cookies and not just those we use on our website.

First and third-party cookies \- whether a cookie is first-party or third-party refers to the domain placing the cookie. First-party cookies are those set by a website that is being visited by the user, the website displayed in the URL window e.g. [www.wpp.com](http://www.wpp.com/?&sa=D&ust=1544732256560000). Third-Party cookies are cookies that are set by a domain other than that of the website being visited by the user. If a user visits a website and another entity sets a cookie through that website this would be a third-party cookie.

Persistent cookies – these cookies remain on a user's device for the period of time specified in the cookie. They are activated each time that the user visits the website that created that particular cookie.

Session cookie – these cookies allow website operators to link the actions of a user during a browser session. A browser session starts when a user opens the browser window and finishes when they close the browser window. Session cookies are created temporarily. Once you close the browser, all session cookies are deleted.

What do we use cookies for?

Cookies fall into one or more of the categories set out below. This website uses cookies that fall into all the categories. Also we use data from targeting cookies placed on your computer by third parties when you have visited other websites.

  1. Strictly necessary cookies – These cookies enable services you have specifically asked for.

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the website. Without these cookies certain services you have asked for cannot be provided. e,g, the ASP.NET cookie.

  2. Performance cookies – These cookies collect information on the pages visited.

These cookies collect information about how users use a website, for instance which pages users go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies don't collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. They are only used to improve how the website works.

  3. Functionality cookies – These cookies remember choices you make to improve your experience.

These cookies allow the website to remember choices you make and provide enhanced, more personal features. The AddThis cookie provides ‘share this page’ functionality, where a user can email a link from a report to their friends. They may also be used to help provide services you have asked for such as watching a video or commenting on a blog. The information these cookies collect may be anonymised and they cannot track your browsing activity to other websites.

  4. Targeting cookies or advertising cookies – these cookies collect information about your browsing habits in order to make advertising relevant to you and your interests.

These cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. They are usually placed by advertising networks with the website operator's permission. They remember that you have visited a website and this information is shared with other organisation such as advertisers. Quite often targeting or advertising cookies will be linked to site functionality provided by the other organisation.

If you want to delete any cookies that may already be on your computer or device, please refer to the instructions for your file management software to locate the file or directory that stores cookies. If you want to stop cookies being stored on your computer in future, please refer to your browser manufacturer’s instructions by clicking “Help” in your browser menu. Further information on cookies is available at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/?&sa=D&ust=1544732256563000). By deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our website.

Third Party Websites

Our website links to third party sites which we do not operate or endorse. These websites may use cookies and collect your personal information in accordance with their own privacy policies. This privacy policy does not apply to third party websites and we are not responsible for third party websites.

How do we protect your information?

We take appropriate measures to ensure that your personal information disclosed to us is kept secure, accurate and up to date and kept only for so long as is necessary for the purposes for which it is used.

Under 13 year olds

This web site is not intended or designed to attract children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information from or about any person under the age of 13. If you are under 13 years old and wish to ask a question or use this site in any way which requires you to submit your personal information, please get your parent or guardian to do so on your behalf.

How to obtain a copy of your information

You are entitled to ask for a copy of the information we hold about you (for which we may charge a small fee) and to have any inaccuracies in your information corrected. Please contact us using the details set out below.

How to contact us if your information or choices change

If your personal information or your preferences change, you don't want us to send you the information you have requested or if you have any queries about how we use your personal information, please let us know by contacting brandz.website@wpp.com

Changes to this privacy policy

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this privacy policy at any time. You are encouraged to review this privacy policy from time to time.

Contact

You can contact us at [brandz.website@wpp.com](mailto:brandz.website@wpp.com) to discuss any problems with this website.

This privacy policy is governed and construed in accordance with English law.
